It seems that these days it's the European nations who have the tallest men and women.
如今，似乎是欧洲国家拥有最高的男性和女性。
Research carried out by over 800 scientists measuring height trends for different nationalities since 1914 has found that Dutch men and Latvian women now top the height charts.
由800多名科学家进行的一项研究，测量了自1914年以来不同民族的身高趋势，研究发现荷兰男性和拉脱维亚女性现在在身高排行榜上位居榜首。
However, according to the study, it's Iranian men and South Korean women who have shot up the most – they have gained on average more than 16cm and 20cm respectively.
然而，根据这项研究，伊朗男性和韩国女性的身高增长最为显著——他们的平均身高分别增长了超过16厘米和20厘米。
In the UK, the rate of growth for men and women has been the same – 11 cm – with the average male now standing at 178cm and the average female at 164cm, both 5cm shorter than the average Dutchman and Latvian female.
在英国，男性和女性的身高增长幅度相同——都是11厘米——现在英国男性的平均身高为178厘米，女性的平均身高为164厘米，两者都比荷兰男性和拉脱维亚女性的平均身高矮5厘米。
Surprisingly, US men and women have sunk right down in the rankings.
令人惊讶的是，美国男性和女性在排名中大幅下降。
While in 1914, they were ranked third tallest for men and fourth tallest for women, nowadays they are down to 27th and 42nd, and today it's Estonia who has the third tallest men and women.
1914年，美国男性的身高排名第三，女性排名第四，而如今他们分别下降到了第27位和第42位，现在爱沙尼亚的男性和女性身高排名第三。
East Asia has seen the most gain in height — with people in China, Japan and South Korea much taller than they were 100 years ago.
东亚地区的身高增长最为显著——中国、日本和韩国的人比100年前高多了。
The survey found that the world's smallest men are in East Timor, 160cm, and smallest women, 150cm, are from Guatemala, 20cm smaller than Latvian women.
调查发现，世界上最矮的男性在东帝汶，平均身高160厘米，最矮的女性在危地马拉，平均身高150厘米，比拉脱维亚女性矮20厘米。
According to the authors of the study, based at Imperial College in London, genetics are not the sole factor in determining height variation among different nations, as Majid Ezzati, lead scientist of the project explained: "Genes don't change that fast and they don't vary that much across the world.
根据这项由伦敦帝国理工学院的研究人员进行的研究，遗传学并不是决定不同国家身高差异的唯一因素，正如该项目的首席科学家马吉德·埃扎蒂解释的那样：“基因变化不会那么快，而且在全世界范围内基因的差异也没有那么大。
So changes over time and variations across the world are largely environmental."
所以随着时间的推移而产生的变化以及世界各地的差异，在很大程度上是由环境因素造成的。”
Of critical importance were sanitation, healthcare and nutrition, he said, as well as the mother's health and diet during pregnancy.
他说，卫生条件、医疗保健和营养，以及怀孕期间妈妈的健康和饮食都至关重要。
Other surprising findings, relating to how height impacts on people's health and income, have been revealed.
其他一些令人惊讶的发现也揭示了身高对人们健康和收入的影响。
For example, tall people can expect enhanced longevity and they are less likely to suffer from heart disease.
例如，高个子的人预期会有更高的寿命，而且他们患心脏病的可能性更小。
Tall people are also likely to earn more!
高个子的人也更有可能挣得更多！
According to research by Exeter University, a British man who is 7.5 cm shorter than his counterpart will earn £1,500 less!
根据埃克塞特大学的研究，一名比同龄人矮7.5厘米的英国男性收入会少1500英镑！
It might be time to invest in a pair of shoes with heels!
也许是时候买一双高跟鞋了！